She's having my baby,
and she's not here yet.
아직 안 왔어, 올 때가 됐는데
왜 아직 안 오는 거야?
괜찮을 거야
양수 아직 안 터졌지?
-Has her water broken yet?
-I don't know.
몰라, 점액질이 쏟아지는
시기는 지났다고 들었어
When we talked, she said she'd
already passed the mucous plug.
Do we have to know about that?
그런 것까지 알아야 돼?
What'll you do
when you have a baby?
조이, 너 아기 낳을 때는
뭐할 건데?
대기실에 가서 담배나
나눠주고 있지
I'll be in the waiting room,
handing out cigars.
Joey's made arrangements to have
his baby in a movie from the '50s.
조이는 50년대 영화 찍으면서
아기를 낳기로 했거든
왜 아직 안 오는 거야?
택시 안에서 낳으면 어쩌지?
She could be giving birth in the cab.
Relax. It's only $2
for the first contraction...
로스, 진정해
처음 진통엔 2달러, 진통 때마다
추가 요금 50센트씩밖에 안돼
...and then 50 cents for each
additional contraction.
왜, 챈들러는 괜찮고 난 안돼?
What, it's okay
when Chandler does it?
You have to pick your moments.
때를 가려서 해야지
Did I miss it?
벌써 낳은 거야?
아직 오지도 않았어
-She's not here yet.
-What's with the guitar?
기타는 웬 거야?
한참 있을 거잖아
음악이 필요할 것 같아서
We might be here for a while.
Things might get musical.
-Where have you been?
-We stopped at the gift shop.
어디 갔다 이제 와요?
- 선물가게 들렀다 왔어요
- 거긴 뭐하러요?
인형 사려고 들렀는데 수잔이
초콜렛을 사겠다고 해서
I got this,
and Susan wanted a Chunky.
초콜렛을 사겠다고?
You're having a baby.
You don't stop for Chunkies.
아기를 낳을 건데
그런 걸 뭐하러 사자고 해요?
난 범퍼 스티커로 쓰는데
I used to have that bumper sticker.
You see what I mean?
농담은 이렇게 하는 거야
The One With the Birth
초콜렛이라니
-"Stopped for a Chunky."
-Let it go, Ross.
그만해, 로스
하나 있는데 줄까요?
I got an extra one.
You want this?
됐어요
우리 부모님들 어떠십니까?
-How's my favorite parenting team?
-Dr. Franzblau.
프란즈블라우 박사님,
안녕하세요
아기를 낳을 생각이시겠죠?
I understand you're thinking
of having a baby.
I see you're nine months pregnant.
That's a good start.
9개월 되셨군요
출발이 아주 좋습니다
-How are your contractions?
-I love them.
진통은 어떻습니까?
아주 좋아요, 자궁에서
파티라도 하는 느낌이에요
Each one's like a little party
in my uterus.
4분 간격이고 55초씩
계속돼요
-Every 4 minutes, lasting 55 seconds.
-59 seconds. Quartz.
59초네요, 내가 맞아요
내 건 스위스 시계예요
Swiss quartz.
뭐 좀 마셔도 돼요?
-Am I allowed to drink anything?
-lce chips.
얼음만 조금 드세요
간호사실에 있을 거예요
-At the nurse's station.
-I'll get it!
- 내가 가져올게
- 아니, 내가 가져올게
- 기다려
- 내가 가져올래
-No, I'll get it.
-No, I'm getting it.
안녕?
얼음이 필요할 것 같아서요
Hi. Thought you might like
some ice chips.
고마워요
-Thanks.
-And if you need anything else l...
필요한 게 있으면...
우리 만난 적 없죠
안녕하세요
...do not believe we've met.
레이첼 그린이에요
캐롤 전남편 동생의 룸메이트죠
I'm Rachel Greene.
I'm Carol's ex-husband's
sister's roommate.
만나서 반갑습니다
전 프란즈블라우 박사예요
Nice to meet you.
I'm Dr. Franzblau.
아가씨 룸메이트 오빠
전부인의 산부인과 의사죠
I'm your roommate's brother's
ex-wife's obstetrician.
재밌네요
Oh, that's funny.
나도 아이 갖고 싶어
I want a baby.
Not tonight, honey.
I got an early day tomorrow.
오늘은 안돼, 자기야
내일 일찍 일어나야 되거든
일어나, 커피나 마시자
-Get up. Let's get some coffee.
-Okay, because we never do that.
그래,
제발 한번 마셔보자
슛, 슛, 슛!
Shoot, shoot, shoot.
Or just fall down. That's good too.
아님 그냥 놓든가
그래, 잘했어
- 닉스 팬이에요?
- 그럼요
Knick fan?
거긴 꽝이잖아요
-Oh, boy, do they suck.
-Listen, lady
뭐요? 이봐요...
Look. Look at your man, Ewing.
봐요
유잉을 보라구요, 슛은 잘 쏘지만
배에 서있으면 물도 못 만질걸요
He couldn't hit water
if he was standing on a boat.
댁은 어디 팬인데요?
-And who do you like?
-Celtics.
- 셀틱스
- 셀틱스?
Celtics? They couldn't hit a boat if
배에 서있으면...
Wait....
잠깐
거기도 꽝이라구요
They suck, all right?
팀을 재정비하는 시기라...
Shut up.
It's a rebuilding year
애아빠를 불러올게요
Let me get the father.
We need a father over here.
아이 아빠 어디 계세요?
아이 아빠 없어요?
없어요
There's no father.
미안해요
-Oh, sorry.
-That's okay. I'm fine.
괜찮아요, 난 괜찮아요
좋아요, 이리 들어가요
Okay. Right this way.
임산부들은 다 이쪽으로
가더라구요
All the other pregnant women
seem to be going in here.
그래요
아직은 작고 귀엽고 예쁘지만
They're tiny and chubby
And so sweet to touch
But soon they'll grow up
And resent you so much
나이가 조금씩 들면서
엄마아빠한테 마구마구 대들죠
엄마아빠한테 소리를 지르는데
엄마아빠는 이유도 몰라요
Now they're yelling at you
And you don 't know why
울고 또 울어 젖혀요
And you cry and you cry
And you cry
울고 또 울고 또 울고...
And you cry and you cry
And you cry
고마워, 로스
-Thanks, Ross.
-I'm paying you to stop.
그만하라고 주는 거야
알았어
저기 봐, 쌍둥이야
귀여워라, 너무 귀엽다
Oh, look, twins.
Hi, guys. Oh, cute.
너무해
No fair.
난 아이가 하나도 없는데
저 사람은 둘이나 되잖아
I don't even have one.
How come they get two?
너도 갖게 될 거야
-You'll get one.
-When?
언제?
우리 이렇게 하자
Tell you what. When we're 40,
if neither of us are married...
우리가 마흔이 됐는데도
둘 다 결혼을 안하고 있으면
우리 둘이 결혼해서 아이를
갖는 거야
...what do you say we have one?
내가 마흔까지 왜 결혼을
못하는데?
Why won't I be married
when I'm 40?
아니, 그런 게 아니라
만약의 경우에 말야
I just meant hypothetically.
그러니까 만약의 경우에
내가 마흔까지 왜 결혼을 못해?
Hypothetically, why won't I be
married when I'm 40?
아니, 아니...
이유가 뭐야? 말해봐
내가 결혼 못할 이유가 뭐야?
What is it? Is there something
unmarriable about me?
말해
Well?
신이시여
낙하산이 왜 안 펴집니까?
Dear God!
This parachute is a knapsack.
안녕
쫙 빼입고 왔네
Look at you, dressy-dress.
옷 갈아입고 왔어?
Did you go home and change?
오늘은 중요한 날이니까
근사하게 보여야지
It's an important day.
I want to look nice.
프란즈블라우 박사님 오셨어?
Has Dr. Franzblau been by?
아니, 못 봤어
I haven't seen him.
어디 계시지?
여기 계셔야 되는데...
Where is he?
He is supposed to be here.
아기한테 필요하면 어떡해
What if the baby needs him?
레이첼, 너랑 의사랑
무슨 상관인데?
What's the deal with you and doctors?
Is your father a doctor?
아빠가 의사라도 돼?
응, 왜?
Yeah. Why?
그냥
No reason.
엄마, 다 끝났어요
Mom, we've been through this.
싫어요, 전화 안 해요
No, I am not calling him.
그 사람 아이든 말든
상관없어요
I don't care if it is his kid,
the guy's a jerk.
아뇨, 혼자 아니에요
조이가 있어요
No, I am not alone.
Joey's here.
조이 누구냐구요?
What do you mean "Joey who"?
Joey who?
트리비아니
-Tribbiani.
-Joey Tribbiani.
조이 트리비아니래요
그래요, 알았어요
잠깐만요
Yes. Okay. Hold on.
- 엄마가 바꾸래요
- 싫어요
She wants to talk to you.
어서 받아봐요
Take the phone.
안녕하세요, 저예요
Yeah, it's me.
아뇨, 우린 그냥 친구예요
No, we're just friends.
네, 혼자예요
Yeah, I'm single.
25살요
Twenty-five.
배우요, 여보세요?
An actor. Hello?
- 엄마가 원래 매너가 없어요
- 그래요
She's not much of a phone person.
근데 애아빠는 어떻게 된 거죠?
So, what's the deal
with this father guy?
누군가에게 아기가 생긴다면
본인이 알아야 될 것 같은데요
If someone was having my baby,
I'd wanna know about it.
닉스 팬, 당신한테 누가 그런 거
물었어요? 상관 말아요
Hey, Knick fan, am I interested
in your views on fatherhood? No.
- 알았어요, 가봐야겠어요
- 가요
-Maybe I should just go.
-Maybe you should.
행운을 빌어요
조심하구요
Good luck...
...and take care.
셀틱스 문제가 뭔지 알아요?
선수들이 멋대로라는 거죠
The Celtics problem is that
the players run the team.
- 그런 소리 말아요
- 정말이에요
-That is so not true.
-Oh, it is.
- 아뇨
- 정말이요
아뇨
- 숨 쉬어
-Breathe.
나 죽이려고 그래?
You're gonna kill me.
15초 더
14초, 13초, 12초...
-Fifteen more seconds. 1 4, 1 3, 1 2
-Count faster.
- 더 빨리!
- 괜찮을 거야
다 조디를 위해서야
조디만 생각하는 거야
It'll be okay. IKeep focusing on Jordy.
He'll be here soon.
4초, 3초, 2초...
조디가 누구예요?
-Three. Two. Who the hell is Jordy?
-Your son.
당신 아들요
조디란 이름이 왜 나와요?
제이미라고 하기로 했잖아요
I don't have a son named Jordy.
We all agreed on Jamie.
제이미는 수잔의 여자친구
이름이라 조디로 다시 합의봤어
Jamie was the name
of Susan's first girlfriend...
...so we went back to Jordy.
다시 합의봤다고?
조디로 합의본 적 없어
What do you mean, back to Jordy?
We never landed on Jordy.
그동안 나온 이름은 제시,
코디, 딜런 뭐 그 정도였잖아
We just passed by it during the whole
Jesse-Cody-Dillon fiasco.
Ow! Leg cramp!
다리에 쥐가 나
- 뭐, 뭐?
- 왜 그래?
-I got it.
-I got it. I'm doing it.
- 알았어
- 내가 할게
당신은 호흡이나 맡아요
다리 쥐는 내가 맡을 테니
You get to sleep with her.
I get the cramps.
아뇨
No, you don't.
그만하고 둘 다 나가
That is it.
I want both of you out.
- 뭐? 이 여자가 시작했어
- 이 사람이 시작한 거야
-She started it.
-He did.
상관없으니까 두 사람 다
나가줘, 나 좀 가만두란 말야
I'm trying to get
a person out of my body here...
...and you're not making it
any easier! Now go!
어서 나가!
- 고맙군요
- 당신 탓이에요
-Thanks.
-See what you did?
- 있지...
- 나가
-Listen
-Out!
숨 쉬어요, 숨 쉬어요
숨 쉬어요
Breathe. Breathe.
이런!
이게 뭐예요?
뭐가 터졌어요
What is that? Something exploded.
아기 나오는 거죠?
-That's not the baby, is it?
-Her water broke. Calm down.
양수가 터진 거예요
흥분하지 말아요
터져요? 그게 무슨 소리예요
뭐가 터졌다는 거예요?
Water breaking?
What do you mean? What's that?
숨 쉬어요, 숨 쉬어요
숨 쉬어요
Breathe. Breathe.
난 괜찮아요
속이 뒤집어지긴 하지만...
I'm okay. I'm okay.
That's disgusting. I'm okay.
다 당신 잘못이에요
-This is so your fault.
-How is this my fault?
왜 내 잘못이란 거죠?
당신 오기 전엔 캐롤은
날 쫓아낸 적이 없어요
Carol never threw me out
of a room before you.
내가 오기 전에 못해본 게
많았을 걸요
There's a lot of things
Carol never did before me.
지금 장난하는 겁니까?
-Are you trying to be clever?
-You're so threatened by me.
당신 문제가 뭔줄 알아요?
나 때문에 위협을 느끼는 거예요
- 내가 말하는 건 다 불만이죠?
- 내가 위협을 느낀다고?
Hey. Okay, all right.
That's it. Get in here.
그만들 하고 안으로 들어가요
왜들 이래요?
My God, you guys.
I don't believe you.
너무하잖아요
아이들이 세상에 처음
태어나는 순간인데
There are children
coming into the world here...
두 사람 부정적인 목소리를
맨 처음 들어야겠어요?
...and your fighting isn't
the first thing they should hear.
소리 좀 그만질러요
그만!
So stop all the yelling!
Just stop it!
그래요
다시는 소리지르게 만들지 마
나도 이런 목소리 싫어
Don't make me do this again!
I don't like my voice like this!
알았으면 문 좀 열어봐
Who wants to hear something ironic?
아직 안 왔어요?
Are they here yet?
아직 안 왔지만 우리가
있으니까 걱정 말아요, 알았죠?
Don't worry,
we're gonna find them.
And until we do,
we are all here for you. Okay?
- 알았어요
- 좋아요
근데 파리 얘기는 듣기만 해도
정말 근사하네요
You were telling me
about Paris. It sounds wonderful.
호텔 바로 옆에 근사한
빵집이 있었는데...
There was this great little
pastry shop right by my hotel
괜찮아요
There you go, dear.
- 찾았어?
- 커피숍, 식당 다 뒤져봤어
-You find them?
-Not in the gift shop or cafeteria....
피비랑 조이는?
Where are Phoebe and Joey?
불길한 일이 일어나고 있어
There's something sinister
going on here.
하다 못해 신체 일부라도
찾게 되면 소리를 질러
If you find anyone,
or parts of anyone...
...scream. And scream again.
지르고 또 질러!
살려줘요!
-Help!
-Come on!
문 좀 열어요
곧 아기가 태어난다구요
-I'm having a baby in there!
-Hello!
- 도와줘요!
- 도와줘요
뒤로 물러서
Okay, everyone stand back.
Ow.
괜찮아
병원이라 다행이다
All right, good thing
we're in a hospital.
리디아, 할 수 있어요
Come on, Lydia, you can do it.
힘줘요, 힘줘요, 더 세게
더 세게, 더 세게...
Push him out, push him out.
Harder, harder.
Way out.
공을 잡았으면 냅다 던져요
헤이 헤이...
Let's get that ball and really move.
Let's get
그러니까 내 말은...
I was just Yeah, okay.
Push, push, push.
힘줘요, 힘줘요
뭐하는 거예요?
문을 빨아들이려구요?
What are you gonna do,
suck the door open?
도와줘요!
Help! Help!
- 도와줘요
그 날 밤 그들은
시체로 발견됐네
And they found their bodies
The very next day
그들은 시체로 발견됐네
And they found their bodies
The very next
도와줘요!
엄마, 걱정하실 거 없어요
오빠도 잘 있어요
Mom, everything's going fine.
Ross is great.
지금 다른 데 있어요
He's in a whole other place.
괜찮아요
No, he's gone.
아뇨, 오실 필요없어요
No, you don't have to fly back.
Really.
유일한 기회일지 모른다니요?
What do you mean "This might be your
only chance"? I'm only 26.
그만 좀 하세요
난 26살이에요
아직 아기 생각도 안해봤다구요
I'm not even thinking
about babies yet.
어디 갔다 왔어?
-Where have you been?
-I just had a baby.
방금 아기 낳았어
재주도 좋다
Mazel tov.
한 시간이 될 수도 세 시간이
될 수도 있지만 걱정말아요
It could be one hour or three.
But relax.
She's doing great.
그런데, 누구 사귀는 사람
있어요?
So tell me, are you currently
involved with anyone?
아뇨, 지금은 없어요
Not at the moment, I'm not. Are you?
선생님은요?
아뇨
누굴 만나기가 쉽지 않아요
No, it's hard enough to get women
to go out with me.
맞아요, 귀여운 의사분들 얘기
많이 들었죠
Right. Yeah, I've heard that
about cute doctors.
그런 게 아니에요
너무 오랜 시간을 보내거든요
아기집에서요
No, really. I suppose it's because
I spend so much time, you know...
...where I do.
일과 사생활을 따로 구분하려고
노력하지만
I try not to let work
affect my personal life.
이런 일을 하다보면...
But it's hard when, when you do
what I do. It's, like....
근데 무슨 일하세요?
Well, for instance,
what do you do?
웨이트리스예요
I'm a waitress.
일 끝나고 집에 갔을 때
이런 생각 들 때가 있지 않아요?
Aren't there times when you come home
at night and you're, like:
커피 한 잔만 더 봤다간...
"If I see one more cup of coffee...."
맞는 말씀이에요
Gotcha.
- 친구분한테 가볼게요
- 그러세요
-I'm gonna check up on your friend.
-That's fine.
나 여기 있는 거
어떻게 알았어?
-How'd you know I was here?
-Your mom called me.
어머님께서 전화하셨더라구
이 아기야?
So is this her?
아니, 빌려온 애야
No, this is a loaner.
우리 아긴 가게에 있어
Ours is at the shop.
우리 아이를 데려올걸 그랬네
God, I hope she has my brains.
당신 혼자 이런 일을
겪게 해서 미안해
I'm sorry you had to do this
by yourself.
혼자가 아니었어, 의사, 간호사,
도와준 친구도 있었고
I wasn't by myself. I had a doctor,
a nurse and a helper guy.
어느 팀이 이겼는지 봤어?
-So did you see who won the game?
-The Knicks by 10. They suck.
닉스가 10점차로 이겼지
꽝이야
그렇게 형편없진 않네
They're not so bad.
제발, 열려라
Come on. Come on.
너무 세게 돌리는 거 아녜요?
-You're doing it too hard.
-You have to do it hard or else
세게 돌려야 열리죠
제길, 빌어먹을!
다 당신 탓이에요
Damn it. Damn it.
Damn it, damn it.
This is all your fault.
내 인생 최고의 날이
될 수 있었다구요
This should be
the greatest day of my life.
내 아들이 태어나는데
My son is being born,
and I should be in there.
옆에 있지도 못하고
창고에나 갇혀있다니
Instead, I'm stuck
in a closet with you.
나도 당신 만큼이나
이 순간을 기다렸어요
I have been waiting for this
as much as you.
천만에, 나보다 이 순간을
기다린 사람은 없어요
No one's been waiting
for this as much as I have.
아이가 태어나면 당신은
아이랑 집에 가겠지만
You know what's funny?
You go home with the baby.
Where does that leave me?
난 뭐죠?
당신은 아이 아빠잖아요
누구나 당신을 알아요
You're his father.
Who am l? There's Father's Day.
There's Mother's Day.
하지만 난 뭐죠?
아빠의 날, 엄마의 날이 있지만
레즈비언 애인의 날은
없잖아요
There's no Lesbian Lover Day.
매일매일이 레즈비언 애인의
날이에요
Every day is Lesbian Lover Day.
너무 좋다
This is so great.
무슨 소리야?
Do you wanna explain that?
나 어릴 때 얘기 알잖아
아빠가 집 나가고 엄마가 죽고
I mean, when I was growing up,
my dad left...
...and my mother died
and my stepfather went to jail.
의붓아빠가 감옥에 가고...
난 제대로 된 부모를
가져본 적이 없어
I barely had enough pieces
to make one whole parent.
근데 이 아기는 부모가
셋이나 되잖아
And here's this baby who has
three whole parents...
자기를 얼마나 사랑하는지
서로 사랑하겠다고 싸우고 있어
...who fight over
who gets to love it the most...
아직 태어나지도 않았는데 말야
...and it's not even born yet.
세상에서 제일 운좋은 아이야
It's just the luckiest baby
in the whole world.
미안해, 계속 싸워
I'm sorry. You were fighting.
어디들 있는 거예요?
Where are they?
곧 올 거예요
-They'll be here.
-They wouldn't miss this.
그럼요, 꼭 올 거예요
걱정하지 마, 9센티밖에 안됐어
아직 멀었어
Relax. You're only at 9 centimeters,
and the baby's at zero station.
넌 정말 무서운 놈이야
You are really frightening me.
누가 나 좀 도와줘
내 심장을 뜯으려고 해
Somebody wanna help me?
Trying to rip out my heart.
누가 내 젖꼭지 못 봤어?
That's great.
Anybody seen a nipple?
좋아요, 10센티
시작해요
Ten centimeters.
Here we go.
좋아요, 힘 줘요
-Time to start pushing.
-But they're not here yet.
아직 안 왔잖아요
아기한테 기다리라고 할 수는
없어요
-I can't tell the baby to wait.
-Oh, God.
맙소사
좋아, 환기구를 열었어
-Okay, got the vent open.
-Hi, I'm Ben.
안녕, 나 벤이야
병원에서 일하는 벤
I'm hospital worker Ben.
벤이 구하러 간다
It's Ben to the rescue.
좋아
벤, 준비됐어?
- 그래
- 좋아, 올라가
Ben, you ready? Give me your foot.
- 그래
- 셋에 하는 거야
하나, 둘, 셋
On three, Ben.
One, two, three.
어서, 벤!
그렇지, 벤, 잘한다
Come on, Ben.
That's it, Ben.
좋아
뭐가 보여요?
What do you see?
수잔, 어두운 환기구로
뭐가 보이겠어요?
I see what appears to be
a dark vent.
잠깐!
Wait.
진짜 어두운 환기구야
Yes, it is, in fact, a dark vent.
피비, 문이 열렸어
Pheebs, it's open.
It's open.
잠깐, 다리도 가져가요
Wait. You forgot your legs.
- 힘 줘, 힘 줘!
- 우리 왔어, 우리 왔어
-Push. Push.
-We're here. We're here.
어디 갔다 왔어?
Where have you been?
얘기가 길어
Long story.
캐롤, 계속 힘줘요
I need you to keep pushing.
I need Excuse me, can I have this?
계속...
이것 좀 집어도 돼요?
안되겠어요
병실에 사람이 너무 많아요
There's too many people here.
There's about to be one more.
전남편이나 레즈비언 커플
아닌 사람은 다 나가주세요
So if you're not an ex-husband or
lesbian life partner, out you go.
- 안녕, 잘 가
- 안녕
- 행운을 빌게
- 행운을 빌어
-Bye-bye.
-Good luck, you guys.
그럼 당신은 캐롤의
레즈비언 커플이에요?
Do you have to be
Carol's lesbian life partner?
나가요
Out.
좋아요, 아이가 나옵니다
Here he comes.
어디 좀 봐요
내가 볼게요
Let me see. I've gotta see.
머리야
A head.
엄청 크다
캐롤, 힘들어서 어떻게 낳아?
It's huge.
How are you doing this?
장난하지 마
You're not helping.
잘하고 있어요, 좋아요
You're doing great.
- 좋아
- 비켜봐요
미안해요
-Hello?
-Oh, sorry.
뭐가 보여요?
What do you see?
머리랑 어깨, 팔이 나왔어
We got a head. We got arms.
Oh, look at the little fingers.
귀여운 손가락 좀 봐
가슴, 배, 그리고 아들이다
틀림없는 아들이야
A chest and a stomach...
...and it's a boy, definitely a boy.
좋아, 다리, 무릎, 발...
Legs, knees and feet.
나왔어...
He's here.
아기가 태어났어
He's a person.
- 저기 봐
- 누구 닮았어?
-Look.
-What does he look like?
젤리 범벅된 에드 삼촌 같아
IKind of like my Uncle Ed,
covered in Jell-O.
정말?
Really?
- 아기 정말 예쁘다
- 고마워, 피비
You guys, he's beautiful.
Thanks, Pheebs.
아직 아기 이름 짓는 일이
남았잖아요
No shouting, but we still need
a name for this little guy.
벤 어때요?
-How about Ben?
-I like Ben.
좋아요
벤
Ben.
벤...
- 좋은데
- 그래
Ben's good. How come you never
mentioned Ben before?
왜 벤 생각은 못했지?
겨우 생각해냈어
We just cooked it up.
그래서 늦은 거야
That's what we were off doing.
- 안녕
- 어서와
- 들어가도 돼?
- 그래, 들어와
-Can we come in?
-Yeah, come on.
I know. I know.
얘들아, 소개할 사람이 있어
Everybody, there's someone
I'd like you to meet.
벤이야
-This is Ben.
-Hi, Ben.
안녕, 벤
- 벤, 친구들이야
- 안녕, 벤
Ben, this is everybody.
수잔, 당신 꼭 닮았네요
Susan, he looks just like you.
고마워요
Thanks.
우리 친구가 아이를 낳았다는 게
믿어지지가 않아
I can't believe one of us
actually has one of these.
그래, 나도 언젠가 낳을 거야
I know.
I still am one of these.
오빠?
안아봐도 돼?
Can l?
그래, 머리야, 조심해
Okay, the head. You gotta....
안녕, 벤
안녕
모니카 고모야
그래, 모니카 고모
I'm your Aunt Monica.
Yes, I am.
난...
항상 껌을 준비할게
I will always have gum.
벤, 아빠가 얘기하고
싶은 게 있어, 살다보면
Ben...
... I want you to know that
there may be some times when...
아빠가 옆에 없을 때도
있을 거야, 이렇게...
... I may not be around like this.
하지만 아빠는 늘
돌아온단다
But I'll still always come back...
이렇게
...Iike this.
어쩌면 오랫동안 떠나있을
때도 있을 거야
And sometimes,
I may be away longer...
이렇게...
...Iike this.
하지만 아빠는 변함없이
돌아온단다
But I'll still always come back...
이렇게...
...Iike this.
3루를 훔치고 싶을 때는
이렇게 하는 거란다
And sometimes, I'll want you to steal
third and I'll go like this:
너무 예쁘다
He is so amazing.
그래, 아기 좀 봐
Yeah, I know. Look at him.
벤?
벤
안녕, 벤
반응이 없잖아
얘 이름이 아닌가봐
Nothing.
I don't think that's his name.
봐, 눈을 감는다
Look, he's closing his eyes.
봐, 눈을 떴어
Look, he's opening his eyes.
너무 느린 거 아냐?
He doesn't do much, does he?
아니, 잘 하는 거야
Nope, this is pretty much it.
- 커피 마실래?
- 그래
You guys wanna get some coffee?
좋아, 나중에 보자
I'll see you guys later.
또 눈 감는다
He's closing his eyes again.